<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>COAsT – Contribution Guidelines</title><link>https://british-oceanographic-data-centre.github.io/COAsT/docs/contribution-guidelines/</link><description>Recent content in Contribution Guidelines on COAsT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://british-oceanographic-data-centre.github.io/COAsT/docs/contribution-guidelines/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Using Hugo</title><link>https://british-oceanographic-data-centre.github.io/COAsT/docs/contribution-guidelines/hugo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://british-oceanographic-data-centre.github.io/COAsT/docs/contribution-guidelines/hugo/</guid><description>
&lt;p>This page will walk you though a simple setup for hugo extended - which is needed if want to view any changes you make to this site locally.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For more details please &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/getting-started/installing/">read this&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="installation">Installation&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="manual">Manual&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Download hugo extended from &lt;a href="https://github.com/gohugoio/hugo/releases">GitHub&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Unzip into preferred location (I use C:\hugo)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add to OS PATH
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>optional but makes usage easier&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="via-a-package-manager">Via a Package Manager&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>On Windows you can use &lt;a href="https://chocolatey.org/">Chocolately&lt;/a> to install with:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre style="background-color:#f8f8f8;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4">&lt;code class="language-shell" data-lang="shell">choco install hugo-extended
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Or on macOS/Linux you can use &lt;a href="https://brew.sh/">Homebrew&lt;/a> to install with:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre style="background-color:#f8f8f8;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4">&lt;code class="language-shell" data-lang="shell">brew install hugo
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;h2 id="try-it-out">Try it out!&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You should now be able to try the following in a terminal&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre style="background-color:#f8f8f8;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4">&lt;code class="language-shell" data-lang="shell">$ hugo --help
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>if you have cloned the COAsT-site &lt;a href="github_repo">repo&lt;/a> you should also now be able to;&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre style="background-color:#f8f8f8;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4">&lt;code class="language-shell" data-lang="shell">$ &lt;span style="color:#204a87">cd&lt;/span> COAsT-site
$ hugo server
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>the above will start a local hugo powered version of the website. you can edit any of the files under /content and see your changes at http://localhost:1313/COAsT/&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Suggested Python Guidelines</title><link>https://british-oceanographic-data-centre.github.io/COAsT/docs/contribution-guidelines/python_guidelines/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://british-oceanographic-data-centre.github.io/COAsT/docs/contribution-guidelines/python_guidelines/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Python as a language comes with more stringent recommendations than most when it comes to code styling. This is advantageous in our case as it gives us an obvious set of guidelines to adopt.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When it comes to simple code styling, much of what&amp;rsquo;s recommended here will be copied from &lt;a href="https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0008/">Python Enhancement Proposal (PEP) 8&lt;/a>, an officially proposed and accepted Python style guide.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="code-styling-conventions">Code Styling Conventions&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s keep things simple to start with&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Indentation should be achieved with spaces rather than tabs and each new level of indentation should be indented by four columns (i.e four spaces).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Any single line, including its indentation characters, should not exceed 79 characters in length.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Top-level (i.e at the module/file level rather than inside a function or class) function and class definitions should be separated by two blank lines.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Method (functions within a class) definitions are separated by a single blank line.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Usually, &amp;ldquo;import&amp;rdquo; statements should be on separate lines, that is to say that you should have one line per distinct module or package import. An exception to this rule is when multiple objects are imported from a single module or package, using a &amp;ldquo;from&amp;rdquo; statement, in which case individual objects can be imported on the same line, separated by commas.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>PEP 8 does not make a recommendation relating to the use of double or single quotes in general use, but for the sake of consistency, this document suggests the use of double quotes wherever practical. This recommendation is intended for the sake of consistency with triple-quoted strings, as per Docstring Conventions (PEP 257).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Operators should be separated by single columns (i.e one space) either side, unless inside parentheses, in which case no whitespace is required.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Comments (beginning with the # character) should be indented as if they were code. In the case of inline comments, separate the comment with two spaces following the code it shares the line with.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>All functions should contain a docstring, which provides basic information on its usage. For this project, the &lt;a href="https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0287/">reStructuredText docstring format&lt;/a> is suggested.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When it comes to naming variables and functions, snake case (lower_case_words_separated_by_underscores) is preferred. There are however a few exceptions to this rule:
Class names should be styled as camel case (EveryNewWordIsCapitalised).
Constants (Variables that should not be changed) can be indicated by the use of screaming snake case (UPPER_CASE_WORDS_SEPARATED_BY_UNDERSCORES). Note that this library currently targets Python 3.7, so the use of &lt;a href="https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0591/">typing.Final&lt;/a> official support for constant variables, new as of Python 3.8: is not currently supported.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In general, it is suggested to avoid the use of single-character variable names, but this is acceptable in certain cases, such as when defining coordinates (such as x, y and z), as these will be commonly recognized and enforcing different rules could cause confusion.
PEP 8 advises the following regarding names to avoid:
&amp;ldquo;Never use the characters &amp;lsquo;l&amp;rsquo; (lowercase letter el), &amp;lsquo;O&amp;rsquo; (uppercase letter oh), or &amp;lsquo;I&amp;rsquo; (uppercase letter eye) as single character variable names.&amp;rdquo;
These specific characters should be avoided because they present an accessibility issue, as under many fonts these characters may be difficult to distinguish or completely indistinguishable from numerals one (1) and zero (0).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In the interest of readability, where named iterator variables are required, this document suggests the use of double characters (e.g. &amp;ldquo;ii&amp;rdquo; rather than &amp;ldquo;i&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h1 id="object-oriented-programming">Object-Oriented Programming&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The general principles of OOP are fairly straightforward and well documented, so I won&amp;rsquo;t waste your precious time by regurgitating that particular wall of text here. Instead, I&amp;rsquo;ll focus on some general pointers specific to this language and use case.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In Python, all class attributes are technically public, but semantically, attributes can be designated as non-public by including leading underscores in the name. For instance, &amp;ldquo;my_variable&amp;rdquo; becomes &amp;ldquo;_my_variable&amp;rdquo;. These attributes are generally referred to as &amp;ldquo;protected&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you define a Python class, it is a best practice to inherit from the base object type. This convention stems from Python 2.X, as classes and types were not originally synonymous. This behaviour is implicit in Python 3.X but the convention has persisted nonetheless. Classes defined this way are referred to as &amp;ldquo;new-style&amp;rdquo; classes.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When defining a class that inherits from another, it is important to remember that overridden methods (in particular, this behaviour is important when dealing with __init__ methods) do not implicitly call the parent method. What this means is that unless you want to deliberately prevent the behaviour of the parent class (this is a very niche use-case), it is important to include a reference to the parent method. An example of this is: super().__init__()
This functionality is advantageous as it prevents unnecessary duplication of code, which is a key tenet of object-oriented software.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>